

CANDIDATE, MASTER'S DEGREE, APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY

Summary_

I am a Master of Science (Computer Science) student at the University of Melbourne researching applied cryptography with Vanessa Teague. I have been a programmer for years, and am passionate about education, security, and privacy. Research interests include zero-knowledge proofs, authenticated data structures, and multiparty computation.

Education

University of Melbourne Parkville VIC 3010

M.Sc. (COMPUTER SCIENCE)

B.Sc. (Mathematical Physics)

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS 2015-2018

Experience

University of Melbourne

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jul 2019 - Present

Working with Prof. Shanika Karunasekera to develop and deploy a large distributed cloud-based system for data collection and analytics. The
project allows large volumes of data (e.g. from social media) to be categorised by topic and analysed for patterns.

- Working as a full-stack developer on a Java server and two front-end GUIs in Java and React. Responsibilities include finding and fixing issues, as well as developing new features and system monitoring scripts.
- Assisted the security research group with grant applications.

Blueprint for Free Speech

Developer Liaison Jul 2019 - Present

- Created a revived GitHub presence and website for the Ricochet end-to-end encrypted chat service operating over Tor.
- Helped update the C++ codebase and installation scripts to work with the latest versions of Tor and operating systems.

University of Melbourne

HEAD TUTOR (OBJECT-ORIENTED SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

Jul 2016 - Nov 2019

2019-present

2015-2018

- Managed the tutoring team for a core subject with hundreds of students, liaising between students, tutors, and lecturers.
- Developed major assignments for students, including specifications, marking criteria, and testing methodology.
- Delivered one to two lectures per semester on software tools and alternative paradigms while also teaching two to three tutorials per week.
- Excellence in Tutoring Award (2017), School of Computing and Information Systems

Honors & Awards

2020 Student Registration Grant, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy

Oakland, California,

U.S.A.

2019

Publications

• Eleanor McMurtry, Olivier Pereira, Vanessa Teague. When is a test not a proof? In Submission.

Projects_____

CUDA CCL (https://github.com/noneuclideangirl/cuda-upad/)

University of Melbourne 2019

- A tool to perform connected-component labelling on a large image very quickly using a GPU. Written using CUDA and C++, implementing an algorithm from the literature in a way that had not been successfully done before to maximise performance.
- · Major project for the graduate subject Parallel & Multicore Computing.

Extra-Dimensional Box (https://github.com/noneuclideangirl/extra-dimensional-box)

University of Melbourne

- An implementation of the Bitbox protocol by Dr Aaron Harwood, a peer-to-peer file-sharing system.
- · A Java networking project designed to be efficient and reliable, for use on small computers such as a Raspberry Pi.
- · Major project for the graduate subject Distributed Systems.